Jordan Skinner

Senior Full Stack Developer

+1 (862) 201-5656

Troy, Michigan

linkedin.com/in/jordan-skinner-dev

iordanskinner072@gmail.com

* SUMMARY

Full Stack Developer and system administrator with over 10 years of experience in software engineering and developing new features and apps for different products and companies by using programming tools like React, React-Native, Redux, Vue.js, Angular, JavaScript(ES6), TypeScript, Node.js, Python, Laravel, PHP, Express, Figma and RESTfulAPI. Specialized in frontend with React, TypeScript, Vue.js and backend with Django, Node.js, AWS and Docker. Also specialized in large complex data migration and mining projects, refactoring code for improved performance, and debugging complex internal and external API integrations.

*** WORK EXPERIENCE**

♦ Full stack developer / Narrativ Digital Agency

- **AUGUST 2021 ~ JANUARY 2024**
 - Worked on the admin and customer portals and rewrote them from Vue 2 to React/TypeScript. Introduced CI/CD for the front end via GitHub Actions.
 - Developed a self-guided wizard for creating a dashboard. The front end was done using Angular, and the back end using .Net Core. The database was a SQL server, and T-SQL was used for developing stored procedures.
 - Created unit tests using the Vue Test Utilities framework to perform component testing and designed Cypress tests to complete the end-to-end testing of UI features.
 - Refactored the existing code to improve the performance of a heavy React front-end by talking to Node.js and Express.js via REST API.
 - Worked as a back-end developer with MySQL, MongoDB, Python and Elastic-Search.
 - Developed a project for this company. This included Python web development with Django, API development with API Gateway, as well as working with Lambda, Python, and the Serverless Framework/SAM.
 - Supported and migrated a global suite of tools for tracking panelist data aggregation from legacy infrastructure to AWS.

♦ Senior web developer / BIAC

- **SEPTEMBER 2017 ~ JULY 2021**
 - Designed and developed 10+ RESTful APIs using Node.JS, Express, Nest, PHP, Laravel, Python, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, MySQL, Redis, AWS, Microsoft Azure and Google Cloud Platform.
 - Worked in DevOps with AWS(Amazon Web Services), Docker, Node, and Python development environments and specialized in Jira.
 - Co-led the development of PRNCPL, a single-page application focused on managing data and customers tailored for art shows using Vue and Vuex.
 - Engaged initially as a contractor to upgrade the front end of KeyBank's corporate banking portal, KeyNavigator, from the AngularJS-based Backbase LaunchPad widget architecture to the Angular 8-based Backbase Widget Architecture 3.

- Built a Node.js-based library, which acted as middleware for Express.js and Koa, that automatically
 captured user errors and sent them to a platform that aggregated and visualized them.
- Used various technologies, including cloud providers such as AWS, GCP, Azure, GitHub actions, Jira, Grafana, Prometheus, and alert manager.
- Lead a team of 8 developers in the development of an enterprise platform using React.

♦ Junior web developer / Ladoo

m NOVEMBER 2014 ~ AUGUST 2017

- Fixed bugs, designed websites as a junior web developer. And then designed a project and database, reviewed other team member's code as a lead developer.
- Collaborated with 5 team members to develop, maintain, and improve 10+ web-based applications.
- Created the front end of an invoice management app written in React. It was fully responsive and had a lot of custom inputs and dynamically generated pages.
- Contributed as a part of the team that developed a new webshop app for a large retailer in Croatia.
- Also created a dashboard stats view with charts using the Recharts library.

*** EDUCATION**

University of South Florida 2010-2014

Bachelor of Degree (BD), Computer science

* SKILLS

Frontend: React, React Native, Redux, Angular, Vue.js, JavaScript, TypeScript, jQuery, Tailwind CSS

Backend: Node.js, Python, Django, C#, ASP.Net, Express.js, Laravel, Figma, AWS, Docker, Git

Database: Oracle, MySQL, MS SQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Elastic-Search